Name : Arif Iskandar

Phone : +62 822 7327 3558 Email : arif19iskandar@gmail.com Language : Indonesia & English

: Medan Sunggal, Kota Medan Address Experience : 4+ years

PERSONAL DESCRIPTION:

BACK-END DEVELOPER

Back-end Developer with 4+ years of experience in educations application, commercial application, and software development. Participated in integration of new systems with legacy software. Having skills in microservices and monolithic architecture. Performed routine software testing and debugging. Working in many programming languages, such as Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python, Ruby, and more.



EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND:

: Computer Science – S1 – North Sumatera University, Bachelor of

Indonesia | 2016 – 2021

Thesis title : Implementation of PID (Proportional-Integral-Derivative) controller using Arduino and

OpenCV as a control of the prototype automatic car. (Using Java, C++, and Python).

GPA : 3.50 from 4.00

BACK-END DEVELOPER SKILLS:

- Having experience in software engineering, application development or system development in 4+ years
- Excellent understanding of software engineering concepts, algorithm, data structure, database design, OOP, design pattern, and version control system.
- Experienced in creating and managing REST API services.
- Experienced with agile development methodology and SDLC
- Can use versioning and revision control with
- Good knowledge using Laravel, Express JS, and Java Spring Boot.
- Have experience in managing and maintain microservices, AWS and cloud servers.
- Conceptualize and implement solutions for database and data storage
- Have ability to learn new technologies quickly and willingness to read and digest large existing source code and take ownership of complex components or subsystem.

PROGRAMMING LNGUAGES:

Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Kotlin, Go, Ruby, PHP, Kotlin, Dart, C++, C#.

TOOLS:

- Visual Studio Code, Android Studio, XCode, XAMPP, Jupiter Notebook
- GitHub, Bitbucket
- Figma, Adobe XD
- Firebase, MongoDB, Redis, MySQL
- Vercel, WordPress, Heroku

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES:

CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER | PT Sekolah Mudah Indonesia (November 2021 – October 2022) | Full Time

- Monitoring the development and dissemination of technology for external customers, vendors, and other clients to improve and increase business
- Collaboration with team product, team marketing, and analysts to discover best test preparation on dsociety.id (website for students)

- Assist and monitoring the performance of UI/UX Designer and back-end developer in building dsociety.id website
- Intensive collaboration with UI/UX Designer, and back-end developer to ensure our product ready to publish
- Being a front-end developer to develop the website using Next JS framework
- Developed website admin to manage content marketing
- Maintain and monitoring cloud servers

FULL-STACK WEBSITE DEVELOPER | Quran Review (April 2021 – Present) | Remote

- Analyze system requirements for Quran Review's website (event sales, book sales, and articles) with product manager
- Doing website research, design, and concepted the prototypes of Quran Review's website
- Build Quran Review's website using Laravel and Vue JS
- Maintain and monitoring server
- Research, redesign, and rebuild Quran Review's website for better visual presentation, animation, and performance

CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER | Bantu Cuci (Agustus 2019 – June 2021) | Full Time

- Responsible for implementing the use of technology to advance the company
- Build an android application called "Bantu cuci" using Android Studio, to help people connect laundry services
- Create flow chart, DFD, and use case using draw.io
- Publishing the app to Google Play Store

HONORS & REWARDS:

CHAMPION OF MUSHABAQAH TILAWATIL QUR'AN MAHASISWA

University of North Sumatera (January 2020)

 Builded a creative innovation to protect children from sexual content in mobile phones. SEKUCIL "Security for child" designed as layer app to prevent sexual content showing. 2. Make a prototype of the innovation and demonstrate it to the judges.

SILVER MEDAL AIGC (ADVANCE INTERNATIONAL GLOBAL COMPETITION)

Singapore AI-JAM Association and Nanyang Technology University (November 2019)

- 1. Design and build a laundry mobile app as an innovation name "Bantu cuci" to help people connect laundry services. This innovation in collaboration with more than 8 laundry MSMEs in Medan.
- 2. Responsible for publishing the application and all technical issue.

PORTFOLIOS:

• GitHub : github.com/cuunoong

• Website : <u>arifisme.dev</u>

TikTok : tiktok.com/@cuunoong

• YouTube : Arif Iskandar